Riddhi Patel

eClinicalWorks
HealthCare MNC IT Company

April 2016 - Present

Already having offer from two companies M.Tech (IT Systems & Network Security), CEHv9 Certified



Accomplished, motivated and versatile IT security researcher with 4.5 years of experience in industry and academic, seeks the next career challenge to improve my skills and contribute to achieve organization goal by utilizing my knowledge and expertise on a larger scale.

Work History

Software Specialist (R&D, Performance, Security& FastLane- Critical)

- Conduct technology risk assessments before deploying upgraded eMobile application, integrations with EMR (eClinicalwork's Desktop App.)
- Finding XSS, SQL injections and other web application vulnerabilitie, report to development, Check configuration in tomcat and scheduled mass deployment. [Taking care for multiple projects]
- Expertise to resolve any challenging issues related Tomcat, Database and Application code. [JAVA]. Also Expertise in Stuck threads analysis, Tomcat Out of Memory, CPU Spiking on SAAS servers, hprof analysis, SSL Handshake.
- Lead the technical security assessments by collaborating with crossfunctional teams such as Developers, infrastructure security testing, perimeter security reviews, data privacy team (Patient Safety), HIPPA violence team as well as few other teams in US.
- Document the risk findings and technical recommendations to remediate in formal reports and present the assessment findings to application owners.
- Lead projects of future security enhancement of existing Product or infrastructure.
- Analysis on findings or Research on new feature for application, Experiment on different analysis, Analyze logs, discuss it with higher level authorities and developers to make product better. Working as Product Expert.
- Expertise in finding any query which is responsible in slow performance of application, Optimization of Query, Plan guide of Query in MSSQL.
- Expertise to find Network issue like legacy in client Network, delay in ISP, etc. Able to find root cause immediately for issues like Application Working slow, Freezing or Not working, able to handle critical Escalations.

Career Power

Dec 2016 - Feb 2017

Valency Networks (Pune) Providing Security Services

Dec 2016 - Dec 2017

Expert Faculty (IBPS/SBI IT Specialist Officer) (Part time)

- Served as an Expert for IT specialist officer batch in week end.
- Performed as a Trainer to almost all IT subjects

Vulnerability Assessment & Compliance Blog Writer (weekends)

 Under Guidance of Prashant Pathak(CEO) of valency network, writing blogs on web security Application, Cloud technology, CSRF and other OWASP Vulnerabilities.

Parul University

June 2013 - June 2015

Assistant Professor

- Teaching Masters of Computer Engineering and Bachelor of Engineering Students.
- Conducted **Expert Lectures** for use of Forensics Tools.
- Guide for Post Graduation Students for their Research work.
- Associated with GTU as an Internal Guide panel to Assessment and review of PG Student Research.
- Patent filing Coordinator for BE Students.

C-DAC Pune

June 2012 - May 2013

Research Trainee

Topic: Analysis of VoIP forensic with Digital Evidence Procedure

Guide: Aditya Sinha (Principal of C-DAC Pune)

Co-Guide: Manu Zacharia (Information Security Evangelist with 22+ yrs of

experience. Microsoft MVP (2009-2012), ISLA-2010 (ISC))

Tools Required:

Asterisk Server, SIP Client

Description:

The main goal of this research is the discussion of security issues of SIP, which serves as a signaling protocol for VoIP services. This work especially concentrates on the security risks of SIP Authentication proposed for VoIP forensic analysis. VoIP spoofing is being a common and most important threat to the VoIP users. Attackers and spammers equently spoof identities in order to be untraceable. It is technically possible for an attacker to masquerade as another VoIP caller (VoIP spoofing).

Android Mobile App: Physical Document Transformation

Article published in national news, media for most Innovative project.

Publisher Name: Divya Bhaskar Date: 20th April 2014

Patent Title: Physical Document Transformation **Patent/Application Number:** 57071/2014-CO/SW

Description:

This is a Researched Project Whose Basic Concept is to Switch the Original Driving License and Registration Certificate Book in Cell Phone Application Which will provide relief from carrying original document. Project has been filed for patenting and

reviewed by Shri. JP Gupta IAS Commissioner of Gujarat Transport.

Intern Developer

Project Title: Online Lease Application Portal

- Analysis, Design and coding of whole project.
- Designed database and created tables.
- Wrote technical documentations in IEEE format.
- Designed work flow Diagram, Flowcharts, Class diagram

Technology/Language used: C#.NET, Microsoft SQL Server 2005 (LINQ)

Brief Description: "Online Lease/Permit Application Portal System" will provide a license to apply, Renew, Transfer, Surrender Lease/Permit for Major and Minor Minerals. OLAP is a system that providing platform for Leaseholder to apply Lease for Major and Minor Minerals. Applicant can Show their Status and can edit and Update their Application by using a unique reference no and Password Provided by System.

Achievement (Patent)

April 2014

(n)Code Solution GNFC

Research Area

Research Publications

VoIP Forensics

Analysis of SIP Authentication in VoIP

Android Application Security

Analysis and security testing of Android system by malware Detection in networks

Application Security

Improving the Security of SSO in Distributed Computer Network using Digital Certificate and one Time Password

Master of Engineering

Specialization: IT Systems & Network Security

M.tech Curriculum included System security, Application security and Cyber forensics.

- Excellent understanding of Internet & Network Security infrastructure
- Good exposure to Penetration Testing along with Trojans and Sniffers.
- Understanding of IDS, Honeypot & firewalls.
- Knowledge of Web application Vulnerabilities.
- Cyber Forensic & Malware Analysis.
- Knowledge of protocols such as VoIP, SIP

IT Skills

- Expert in troubleshooting of any Application hosted on Tomcat Server,
 Finding Slow thread, Analyze code.
- Able to Troubleshoot of any Network Dropping or Midstream ISP dropping
- Excellent Security Research skill
- Knowledge of OS Kalilinux, Android
- Knowledge of Asterisk server, Source insight, Virtual Box, WebGoat Vulnerable Application
- Languages: C, JAVA(basic), Android(basic), SQL, PL-SQL, HTML
- Knowledge of OWASP top 10 vulnerabilities and Socket Programming.
- Excellent Analytical and Reasoning Skill
- Tools/Softwares MAT, Metasploit, Snort IDS, VoIP spoofing, Wireshark, Fiddler, netstat, Ethercap, Nessus, TCP Dump, IP Tables, Proxy, Cisco Packet Tracer, Nslookup, fping, Nmap, SQLMap, Netdiscover, Netscan, Hydra, SET(Social Engineering Toolkit), TraceRoute, pathping, WinMTR, Burp Suite, Hping3, Forensic tool kit(FTK) imager, COFFE etc.

Education

Gujarat Technological University

Jun 2011 - Jun 2013

Gujarat University

C-DAC

Gujarat Tech. Uni.

GTU

Aptech institute

Sai Institute

L.J.Institute of Engg.

Jun 2007 - Jun 2011

M.E. CE (IT Systems and Network Security)

Grade Obtained: Distinction

B.E. Information Technology

Grade Obtained: Distinction

Certifications, Workshops & Projects

EC-Council Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH |v9)

Workshop on High Performance Computing

Oracle Academy Database Design and Programming with SQL

International Patent filing Procedure Certificate

Certification in Developing Application in Core Java

Certification in Developing Application in ASP.NET

Online Examination Portal (.NET Technology)

Achievements

- Received Appreciation from site head at the time of Appraisal for dedication towards work and for working above and beyond of my hired profile and became the only employee in the team who got 61% of hike.
- Participated in the event of Hackathon and in a day suggested more than 10 ideas for technical structure changes which are accepted by developers and received extra bonus for this.

Strengths

- Self-confident & Goal oriented.
- Hardworking & Self Motivated.
- Good ability to Solve Problem.
- Good Decision making skill
- Excellent Analytical and Reasoning Skill.
- Always enjoy challenging tasks

Reference

Aditya K. Sinha (Guide) Principal C-DAC Acts, Pune, Maharastra.

Email: saditya@cdac.in

Languages

English Hindi Gujarati

Place: Ahmedabad Date: 21/11/2018

Riddhi Patel